♪ Welcome to L.A. ♪
♪ Another sunny day ♪
♪ In Californ-i-a ♪
♪ Hey-hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ It's good to be here ♪
♪ I really have to say ♪
♪ That life's a holiday ♪
♪ So throw your worries away ♪
♪ Hey-hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Welcome to L.A. ♪
♪ Yeah, welcome to L.A. ♪
♪ Another sunny day ♪
♪ In Californ-i-a ♪
♪ Buh-do, buh-do
Buh-do, do, do, do ♪
♪ Duh-duh do, do, do ♪
So when are you
producing your movie?
Well, the script's
finally in shape.
Location's all lined up.
Heh. The director's
champing at the bit.
So why aren't you in production?
Well, we're still
waiting for the studio
to give us a go-ahead.
You'd better get it soon.
This party's gonna
cost you a bundle,
if I have anything
to do with it.
Heh. At the rate you're
going, it sure as hell will.
Go on. Heh-heh.
Hey. What are you
doing here, man?
Thought you were up in
Fresno, expanding the kingdom.
Yeah, what did you sell,
one, uh, franchise before lunch
and three after?
No, no, no. Four.
Get out of here.
Adam. Hey, Adam.
Glad you could make it, my man.
When I called, you said
you weren't feeling well.
You were spending
the evening at home.
I felt better.
Felt like going out
behind my back.
Adam, cool it.
I felt like going out.
Come on. We're
leaving. No, you leave.
I'm having a good
time. I said we're leaving.
All right, it's getting
kind of crowded in here.
Come on. Hey, knock it off, man.
Let go.
Let go, man! Let go!
Hey, take it easy. What
is the matter with you?
Hey!
He's not worth it.
All right. All right.
Hey, Adam. Come on.
Are you all right?
Look, it's not like Deb's
my date or anything.
I just thought with you
out of town, that she
might like some company.
Yeah, come on. Lighten up.
There's a lot of
available girls in there.
Adam, I'm really sorry.
Come on. Let's go back in.
No, no, no. No.
I'm gonna take a drive,
up the coast or something.
I don't know.
Come on, Adam.
Let him go.
Come on.
Where's Adam?
He left.
Was he very upset?
He's gonna get over it.
I gotta go.
He won't be home.
He went for a drive.
Well, then, I'll wait for him.
♪ Right from the start ♪
♪ You have been so afraid ♪
♪ To open up ♪
♪ Your heart ♪
♪ Why can't you see? ♪
♪ Love is so beautiful ♪
♪ If you can let in me ♪
♪ A little bit more ♪
♪ A little bit more, baby ♪
♪ Just a little bit more ♪
♪ Oh, a little bit more, baby ♪
♪ Give your heart to me ♪
♪ Baby, I know... ♪
Mm.
Aah!
♪ It's great to be here ♪
♪ Smack dab in the heart... ♪
Debra!
♪ Where the neon
lights Shine so pretty ♪
♪ I love it all ♪
♪ Life's a ball ♪
Debra!
♪ Welcome to L.A. ♪
Deb?
Somebody's dead.
Who do I call?
How far up the coast did you
say you drove, Mr. Gardner?
North of Santa Barbara.
That's all I know.
Like I said, I got
tired of driving,
so I pulled over,
walked on the beach for a while,
turned around and
drove... Drove home.
Mm.
See anyone on the beach?
No. Not at 5:00 in the morning.
He's already been
over this part of it.
Is there a problem, detective?
Yeah, you could say that.
He tells one story,
the facts tell another.
The facts exonerate my client.
The girl had too much to drink,
she passed out and she drowned.
There was an open
bottle of champagne
right there next to her.
But very little
alcohol in her blood.
Probably whoever killed
her put the champagne there,
wanted people to
think it happened
just the way you
said, but it didn't.
Still could have
been an accident.
She just fell and hit her head.
Only injuries the coroner found
were bruises on
either side of her neck,
suggesting that someone
grabbed her throat
and held her underwater.
Someone wearing your
bathrobe, by the way.
Bottom of the sleeves
were wet with water
containing the same amount
of chlorine as in the pool.
Oh, excuse me,
would you, please?
Damn it.
Take it easy, Adam.
She's dead. Sh...
Carl, she's dead,
and I couldn't even help her.
Look, don't worry
about the case.
I'm not a criminal lawyer,
but I know circumstantial
evidence when I see it,
especially flimsy
circumstantial evidence.
They don't begin to
have a motive here.
Carl, we had a fight.
Debra and I had a bad fight
in front of a dozen people.
Adam, you don't understand.
To get a conviction
in a murder case,
they really need an eyewitness
and they don't have one.
Wrong again, counselor.
We just heard from one
of Mr. Gardner's neighbors.
Says he saw the whole thing.
Uh... my client
declines to answer
any further
questions at this time.
Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Matlock!
Yeah?
Come on in.
Same thing every winter.
We've got this maintenance
man who drinks.
Either I freeze to death,
or it steams up my glasses.
What can I do for you?
I'm Adam Gardner
from Los Angeles.
Oh, yeah.
The young man with
all the cookie stores.
I believe you were expecting me.
I could have sworn there were
all manner of lawyers
in Los Angeles.
Well, my lawyer, he's
not a defense attorney.
You're supposed
to be one of the best.
Look, Mr. Matlock,
I didn't kill Debra.
I loved her.
Someone's framed me.
Yeah. Yeah.
You want me to come all the
way to California to represent you?
Well, I want you to sit
down with my lawyers first,
hear what their advice is
and then give me yours.
Yeah. Well...
you caught me right
at my busiest season.
My daughter's on
vacation and everything.
I'd have to rearrange
my whole schedule.
How much?
It's not a matter of money.
Twenty thousand?
Fifty. Fifty?
For now.
♪ Welcome to L.A. ♪
♪ Another sunny day ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo, doo, doo ♪
The point is, Adam's
not just selling cookies.
He's selling what
cookies stand for.
Youth, vitality, innocence.
A seamy, protracted trial
with all the attendant
negative publicity
could very well drive the
stock right into the ground.
I think it behooves Adam
to get this thing behind him
as soon as possible.
The question is, how?
That's no problem.
The DA's evidence is
grossly circumstantial.
He knows it and we know it.
We just need to negotiate
until we can come up with a plea
that everybody can live with.
What do you think he'll go for?
Voluntary,
hell, maybe even
involuntary manslaughter.
Adam comes home, finds the girl.
Fight starts up again.
They struggle. They argue.
He pushes. She pushes.
Next thing he knows, she's dead.
I think we're talking a
maximum of two years here,
probably even less.
Seems to me that settles it.
Adam, were you
able to follow all that?
You're telling me
to plead guilty?
To involuntary
manslaughter, yes.
Uh, Mr. Matlock,
what do you think?
Did you do it?
No!
I'd plead not guilty.
I appreciate your advice,
but I'm pleading not guilty.
Then I guess this
meeting is adjourned.
Wanna go somewhere
for a root beer?
I think you should
be comfortable here.
I think a whole lot of people
could be comfortable
here, all at once.
Only there was
no way to prove it.
Sounds like they already are.
Now, I know that the only
way I'm gonna break this case
is that I have to
prove that the judge
hid his old clothes, right?
Uh... Oh, Ben.
Ben, we have Mark Williams,
Michael Porter. Hi, sir.
And Josh Sinclair.
Good to see you.
These are Adam's
closest and oldest friends.
Ah. Four of us grew up together.
Yeah, we've been
accused of many things,
but never of growing up.
We went to the same high school.
The jock.
The brains.
And the clown.
And the operator.
Yeah, by those less fortunate,
we were called the Rat Pack.
Oh, ho-ho-ho.
So how are you gonna
break down the DA's case?
I don't know yet.
But if Adam didn't do it,
then it was probably one of you.
That's absurd.
Well, you were the only ones
who knew that Debra
was going to Adam's house
and that she would
there be alone.
Wait a minute. It
could have been
a hillside strangler or a
serial killer or anybody.
That was just a josh.
Just a josh.
I'm sure you wanna help out,
and I'll be talking
with you fellows.
All right.
Yeah. I'll call you later.
Bye, bye. MATLOCK:
See you later.
I'll talk to you later. Yeah.
Oh, sorry.
Just a josh, huh?
Look, Mr. Matlock,
those are my best friends.
There's often a lot
of truth in a little josh.
One of them may not
be your friend at all.
Do you have the key
to Debra's apartment?
I need to look around.
All right.
It's California dip.
Well, Tyler, how are
you liking Beverly Hills?
Ben, this is my spiritual home.
Taxi! There must be an avocado
out there with your name on it.
Almost too many, Ben.
Almost too many.
Well, are we gonna go
to work or go to a funeral?
Compliments of my friend
Mark. He has a limo service.
Mr. Matlock, I'm Jimmy
Bowles, your chauffeur.
Oh. My associate, Tyler Hudson.
Good to meet you.
Ahem, you think we ought to
ride in something a little smaller?
Are you kidding?
Hey, Jimmy, I'm gonna
ride shotgun. Go ahead.
Okay.
Hey, Jimmy, you ever
driven any celebrities?
Heh. You name
them, I've driven them.
Clark and Carole,
Ed and Liz, Frank and Judy,
Frank and Ava, Frank and Mia.
I'm telling you,
if they ever made a
movie about all the things
that went on behind my
back, it'd be rated double X,
and have the
longest run in history.
Jimmy, I'm gonna tell you, I
don't say this to many people,
but you're an amazing man.
Yeah.
Fancy cars and movie
stars, I tell you, Ben,
this is my kind of town.
Uh-huh.
♪ Another sunny day ♪
♪ In Californ-i-a ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ It's good to be here ♪
How much longer till we
get to Debra's apartment?
Relax and enjoy the ride.
The air smells like somebody's
having their dog dry-cleaned.
You smell smog.
I smell paradise.
Well, I'm rollin' up
my window anyway.
♪ Welcome to L.A. ♪
♪ Doo-duh, doo, doo ♪
Uh... You say Debra
was an actress?
Extra, mostly.
Couple of bit parts
last year. Nothing big.
She come from money?
No.
How do you explain that?
Twenty-five thousand dollars?
She deposited that much
every month for at least
the last three months.
She couldn't have had that kind
of money. She would've told me.
Maybe she didn't want
you to know where she got it.
Ben.
What do you think of that?
Who are those from?
"I hate what we're doing,
"I really do, but
I would hate life
without you even more.
Love forever, Josh."
No. You're going home.
Like hell I'm going home.
First things first.
You may have been betrayed,
but your girlfriend
was murdered.
We've got the, uh, mushroom
light in the living room.
We've got the
shaston outside, right?
Get it straight. Mr. Sinclair.
Oh, hey.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
No problem. Heh.
As a matter of fact,
you're a half-hour
early. Oh, it's 11:30.
Oh, I'm sorry. My... My
watch isn't on L.A. time.
You'll have to change it.
Well, my body's
still on Atlanta time.
Could have been worse, though.
I could have shown
up three hours early.
Yeah.
So this is one of
your properties, huh?
Yeah.
What's a place like this go for?
Well, when I get
done with it, uh...
Well, 280, 290.
Two hundred and
ninety thousand dollars?
That's right.
I have a henhouse
bigger than this.
It works. I've been
doing it for a long time.
No kidding.
So, uh,
how long had you
been seeing Debra?
Debra was Adam's girl.
Well, that's what he thought
until he read one
of those letters
that we found in her apartment.
Written by you.
Tsk. Oh, God.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
He read them?
Yeah.
So how often did you see her?
Whenever he was out of town
and sometimes
when he was in town.
She didn't want to
say anything to him
because she... She
didn't wanna hurt him.
Where'd you go after
the party that night?
I went home.
Alone.
Look, I didn't kill her.
Did you ever give her any money?
I offered her some, but, I
mean, she wouldn't take it.
Why? Just curious.
Two hundred and ninety
thousand dollars, huh?
Hey, well, for you, uh...
Yeah. We can do something.
Thanks for the time.
All right.
Oh, I-I'm sure it's a
good read, Jerry, but it...
It's just not right for me.
All right. Look, uh, I gotta go.
Okay. All right. Bye-bye.
Hi. Hi.
Boy, this is some experience.
This?
No. You.
The four of you.
Yeah?
Yeah. Four unique men.
You're young, successful.
You know, uh, you're
the one who's unique.
Certainly one of the best-known
defense attorneys
uh, in the country.
Mm, well.
Any offers to purchase
the rights to your life?
No. What...? What would
you get for a thing like that?
What would you want?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe $25,000 a
month for three months?
Where did you get the figure?
Ah, it seems like
a good going rate.
Ben, out here
everything is negotiable.
Oh, I see.
Where were you at 4:00
the morning Debra
O'Keefe was murdered?
Party I threw ended around
3:30 and I went home.
By yourself?
Yeah.
Oh.
Did you ever have occasion
to give Debra some money,
say, $75,000?
Look, I was nice to
her because of Adam,
but I-I was never that nice.
Hey, Tyler.
Hey.
Where's, uh, Jimmy?
I gave him some money to
take a little trip to Gardena.
They got legalized poker there.
When did you start
subsidizing gambling?
Ever since I found out that
there is something very weird
going on with Mark
Williams' limousine service.
Seems that Jimmy and
some of the other drivers
have been running these
strange errands at night
where they're transporting
things that are put
in their trunk that
they're not allowed to see
for people that they're
not supposed to meet.
Oh. So tonight, you're
taking Jimmy's place?
That's right, and the
address that he starts out on
is on Bellagio,
which is in Bel-Air.
Stay in the car.
Who are you?
Tyler Hudson. Didn't
Jimmy call you?
Yeah, and when he did he
said he'd tell you the rules.
Stay in the car, keep your
eyes forward, and wait.
Now pop the trunk.
Here's the address.
The map is marked.
When you get there, same thing:
Stay in the car, keep
your eyes forward,
pop the trunk and wait.
Then come back here.
The round trip should
take you exactly 43 minutes.
No stops.
Come on. We gotta rush.
They got me on the clock.
What is this
stuff? I don't know.
I have no idea. But
the sooner I get rid of it,
the better I'll feel. Here,
just take some of it.
They'll never
know the difference.
I'll pour a little bit.
Wait, wait, wait.
Okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Just gotta put it
back the same way.
Okay. There you go.
All right.
Close the trunk!
Sir, stop right there.
Turn around, put
your hands up there,
and don't move.
Officer, I know
walking in these parts
is out of fashion but I
didn't know it was illegal.
You live around here?
Nowhere near here.
What's this?
I was hoping you could tell me.
Let's go.
This is ridiculous.
I'm a lawyer
licensed to practice
in the state of Georgia.
I wasn't loitering
or dealing in drugs.
I have no criminal
record whatsoever.
Well, then you have
nothing to worry about, sir.
I suppose even in Beverly Hills
a persons entitled
to one phone call.
Over here.
Operator, in Beverly
Hills for Carl Richardson.
He's an attorney.
Thank you.
Carl, Ben Matlock.
I'm down here at the Beverly
Hills Police Department,
I'm offered free room
and board for the night.
Please come down here
and straighten this out
as soon as possible.
Thanks.
That was two phone
calls, that's your limit.
One was the operator, the
other was an answering machine.
Tough.
Let's go.
Ha-ho. Man, am
I glad to see you.
Ha. Name's Arthur Rydell.
Being in jail is one
thing, being in jail alone...
Oh, talk about your cruel
and unusual punishment.
I'm sorry, I-I didn't
catch your name.
Ben Matlock. Excuse me.
Ben, you think you got troubles.
Ben, Ben, Ben, you
don't know what trouble is.
And neither did I
until two months ago
when that piece of refuse,
then known as my wife,
hit me with the D word: divorce.
Whoa, ho-ho-ho. Heh.
Oh.
Want me to call the police?
Why advertise? TYLER:
Wait a minute, wait...
I know you.
You're S.J. Sweet,
the evangelist.
I seen you on TV.
And what might your
name be, my brother?
Tyler Hudson.
I'm a private investigator.
Yeah, that's right.
He works for Adam
Gardner's attorney.
Where's Jimmy?
I gave him the night off.
Mr. Hudson, what
brings you to my house?
Well, Debra O'Keefe's
murder appears connected
to a small blackmail scam
that's netted about $75,000
in the last three months.
So I wanted to know
what his limo driver's
secret deliveries
were all about.
The Lord's work, that's
what they're about.
Mark is helping me move
my place of residence.
And that's the big secret?
You satisfied?
What's that white
powder in those jars?
A special blend of grain
for my breakfast cereal.
Mark, where were you on
the night of Debra's murder?
I was at home, alone.
Not a very good alibi.
Mine is a high-profile business,
which requires the
cleanest of hands,
which means I have to keep
an eye on the people I deal with.
Lest any dirt on
them rub off on me.
You been having me tailed?
I keep a close
watch on my flock.
When Mark needed some cash
for his business, he came to me.
So he couldn't have
given any money to Debra
without my permission.
I am his solid partner.
N'est pas?
Your secret's safe with me.
I'm sorry about
interrupting your evening
but I want to thank you
for your cooperation.
And for you, brother, I
apologize for any distress
I may have caused you.
As a matter of fact,
I'd like to treat you to dinner
as a gesture of my good faith.
How could we say no?
All right.
We'll drop by my hotel
and get a change of clothes
and then I'm gonna show
you a spot that is so hot.
This town is just...
Then you know what she did?
After she took one half
of everything I ever owned,
she issued a restraining
order against me.
If I came within ten feet of her
they were supposed to arrest me.
I didn't wanna come
within ten miles of her...
only I forgot my golf clubs.
See, I decided to go
to Carmel to play golf,
only I forgot that my golf
clubs were still in my house.
My ex-house.
So I had to sneak
into my own house
to get them back,
only she caught me.
Next thing you know
she's calling the cops.
I figure for as long as it
takes them to get there
I'll be long gone, right?
First time in police history
they are there in two minutes.
See, she had me arrested
to teach me a lesson.
Thinks I'm gonna call her
and beg her to
drop the complaint.
Well, I won't give
her the satisfaction.
I'd sooner cut off my finger
before I dialed that phone.
Excuse me.
The units are the
private investors...
Michael, can I have
a word with you?
Maybe some other time.
Well, it's just a
few small details
that would help out
your buddy Adam.
And I don't believe I've
met this beautiful lady.
Elinor, uh, this is Tyler.
Elinor's a friend of the family.
So, uh, what is it?
Well, you told Ben that
you were home alone
at the time of the murder
but I checked with Adam,
he said he tried to call you
and there was no answer.
That's just a small detail
but if you could help me
out I'd be really appreciative.
You didn't tell him
you were with me?
Elinor, I was trying
to protect you.
From what?
You would rather let him believe
that you had no
alibi for a murder
rather than say
you were with me.
You're that ashamed?
No, no. Hey, look...
He was with me...
all night.
And if you find that
an embarrassment.
Tomorrow I'm withdrawing
the letter of credit,
canceling your credit cards
and all your charge accounts.
See you at the movies, Michael.
Oh.
I had no idea.
I mean, I called the
creep and I'm on the clock.
I mean, "hello"
costs me 5 bucks.
A full sentence costs 10.
I am not gonna call him,
there's no way he's gonna
squeeze another dime out of me.
Have you called anybody
since you were arrested?
Huh, I'd sooner
drink battery acid.
Well, the call you have
coming, give it to me.
Give it to you?
Call somebody for me.
You're gonna leave me?
Arthur, I know for you
being in jail's a
matter of principle.
But it isn't for me.
Ah, I am sorry.
I am sorry. I-I'm being selfish.
Officer!
Hey!
Here. Call Tyler Hudson
at the Bedford Hotel.
Tell him to get down
here as fast as possible.
Hey, officer, I wanna
make my phone call now.
Thank you, bud.
Hi, Buster.
So, uh, who do you wanna meet?
Her.
You can do better than her.
I don't wanna do
better than her.
Ah.
Say, um, there's a guy
sitting over there at the table
all by himself.
Johnny? Johnny?
Johnny Alexander.
That's one guy you
don't wanna meet.
Why not?
My partner over there
says you're doing some
business with Josh. What?
Said my buddy over there
says you been doing...
Now what did you say?
Heard you've been
doing some business
with my friend Josh Sinclair.
Thought that's what you said.
When's he coming?
Well, he wasn't
there. I left a message.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
Doesn't anybody go
to bed in Beverly Hills?
Hey, listen, uh, Ben,
it seems my wife called
and dropped the charges.
So this is adios, good buddy.
Hey, if you ever get
into town look me up,
we'll do lunch.
Tyler!
Tyler! Ben.
Please, not so loud. Tyler.
You know where I was all
night while you were partying?
Ben, please, not so loud.
I was in jail.
Ben, you are looking
at a man in great pain.
You are looking at a man who
sacrificed his body for his job.
Tyler, I was in jail.
Ben, I know.
I called and they
just released you.
They thought I
was a drug dealer.
That powder I
took out of that jar
turned out to be some
kind of powdered cereal.
You know S.J. Sweet,
the TV evangelist?
That was his cereal.
What's a TV evangelist
got to do with anything?
Ben.
Just calm down.
Relax and don't be so loud,
and I'll tell you all
about last night.
I got busted breaking
into S.J. Sweet's house
because that's where the
limos were making the pickups.
Well, it turns out
they're just moving S.J.
from residence to another
under the cover of darkness.
S.J. and I had a chat,
turns out to be a nice man.
He also gives Mark Williams
an alibi for the
night of the murder.
But then I shrewdly
get his bouncer, Buster,
to go with me to one of
the hottest spots in the city,
which also happens to be
Michael Porter's hangout.
There, Michael Porter's
alibi turns out to be a woman.
An angry woman, but
an alibi nevertheless.
May I finish? Finish.
Now, Ben, I am a highly
skilled professional,
and a dedicated one.
Do you think I would hit
five of this city's hottest spots
for fun?
What did you find out?
I found out that
Sinclair had a meeting
with Johnny
Alexander last night.
Alexander is a major
cocaine trafficker.
I find out from Buster
that Sinclair has made
three big deals with Alexander
in the last couple months.
No kidding. No kidding.
Get up.
Ben, I can't.
Two of Alexander's associates
tap danced on my torso
and I have yet to recover.
Get up. Tyler, get up.
No, Ben. No, please.
I need you and Carl Richardson
to do something for me.
This is gonna be
a bonus situation!
All right. A bonus
situation! All right, a bonus!
Get up! Ow, hey, oh.
Now, Mr. Wallingford,
you live next door
to the defendant.
Is that correct?
Yes, it is correct.
Our houses are
perhaps 50 feet apart.
Mm-hm. So then you have
an unobstructed
view of his house?
Yes.
Would you tell the
court what you saw
around 4 a.m. on the
morning of March 11th?
Well... Ahem.
I happen to be
rather a light sleeper
and I was awakened by
loud music from next door.
So I got up and looked
toward Mr. Gardner's house
and I saw a young woman
who is a frequent
visitor of Mr. Gardner's.
Uh, my bedroom is
directly opposite his
so I can see inside.
Oh, it's 2:15.
What's the problem?
The problem is Tyler isn't here.
This is a photograph
of the victim.
Is this the lady you saw?
Yes, that is she.
Where was Miss O'Keefe
when you saw her?
She was in
Mr. Gardner's bedroom.
She was wearing a bathing suit.
Did you see anyone else in the
bedroom through the window?
Yes, Mr. Gardner himself came
into the bedroom after she left
just as I was going back to bed.
Do you have any idea what
time it was when you saw him?
It was exactly 4 a.m.
I looked at the clock
as I was getting into bed.
But Mr. Gardner told
the police that he arrived
at 7 that morning.
Are you sure you
saw him? Positive.
He was wearing
his blue bathrobe.
I've seen him in it many times.
It was not the first
time his music woke me.
Thank you.
Uh, no further
questions, Your Honor.
Your witness, Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Wallingford, I'm
sometimes a light sleeper myself
so I can sympathize with
you about noisy neighbors.
You say Mr. Garner's music
has awakened you often?
Often enough.
So you've had quite
a little experience
of peeping into
Mr. Gardner's bedroom?
Objection, Your Honor.
Sustained.
Now, let...
Let me see if I can
get this straight.
Your window faces directly
across at Mr. Gardner's
and you can look right in there?
Yes.
Uh, bailiff?
Would you mind stepping
down here a moment?
Now, this is an
exact representation
of the French doors
at Mr. Gardner's house,
and have been so
stipulated by the prosecution.
Now, the blinds are the
same way they were that night.
Is that the way you
remember them?
Uh, pretty much like that, yes.
Mr. Gardner, would you
step behind the French door?
Okay.
What do you see?
Mr. Gardner.
All I see is his suit.
Just as all you saw that
night was his blue bathrobe
so you assumed it was
Mr. Gardner, didn't you?
Yes, b... And when
you saw Miss O'Keefe
you didn't focus on
her face either, did you?
Objection.
Your Honor?
No further questions.
Thank you, bailiff.
Thank you, Mr. Wallingford.
You may, uh,
return to the hallway.
About time.
Ben, my head is throbbing,
my legs are shaking.
I'm afraid I'm gonna
pass out if I don't sit down.
Good. You got
everything? Everything.
Next witness.
The prosecution
rests, You Honor.
Mr. Matlock, are you going to
put on a defense at this time?
Yes, we are, Your Honor.
I'd like to call Mr. Joshua
Sinclair to the stand.
Mr. Sinclair, did you know
the decedent, Debra O'Keefe?
Yes, I did.
Yeah, she was dating
one of my best friends, uh,
Adam Gardner.
I show you this
packet of letters
found in Debra
O'Keefe's apartment
and ask if you wrote them?
Yes, I did.
In fact, they're written on
your own personalized
stationary, aren't they?
That's right.
Would it be fair to categorize
them as love letters?
Yeah.
Now, these letters are
arranged in chronological order.
Would you tell the court
when the first three
letters were written.
January 17th, 1986.
Uh... January 20th and the 23rd.
When did you
purchase this stationary?
I don't know.
Well, I have a bill
here from your printer.
You ordered this
stationary March 2nd, 1986.
You picked it up and paid
for it by check March 5th.
You couldn't have
written those letters
when you said you did.
You planted those letters in
Debra O'Keefe's apartment
after she was
murdered, didn't you?
Yeah, I did that, uh,
because I thought I'd
be helping Adam out.
And, uh, you know,
take a little of the heat off,
confuse everybody, you know?
You cast suspicion of
murder on yourself for a friend?
That's right.
You're some friend.
Are you also friends
with a young man
named Johnny Alexander?
Never heard of him.
Isn't it true
that you made three very large,
very profitable cocaine
deals with Johnny Alexander
to cover mortgages on
your commercial property?
No, that's not true.
Isn't it true that Debra
O'Keefe introduced you
to this cocaine dealer
Johnny Alexander,
and you planted these
letters in her apartment
to cover your real
relationship with her?
No.
Isn't it true that Debra
O'Keefe demanded $25,000
each time you and Johnny
Alexander closed a deal?
No, it's not true.
Isn't it true you
murdered Debra O'Keefe
because she demanded
even more money?
No, it isn't true.
None of it's true.
How tall are you?
Six-three.
That's...
five inches taller than
the defendant, right?
Yeah, I guess. Heh.
This is the robe the police
say Debra's killer was wearing.
The bottom of the sleeves
were saturated with
chlorinated water.
Would you mind trying it on?
Your Honor,
there's no relevancy,
nor is there any
foundation here.
Now, they may find
Mr. Matlock's courtroom theatrics
amusing in Georgia,
but we have more pertinent
matters to attend to here
than the fit of a
man's bathrobe.
Your Honor, this
line of questioning
is essential to our case.
I beg your indulgence.
Overruled... for now.
Thank you.
Would you slip off
your jacket, please?
Sure.
There you go.
Now try that on.
That's a little small, isn't it?
Yeah, I guess it is, isn't it?
Especially in the sleeves.
You know what's
always bothered me?
Is that just the bottoms
of the sleeves got wet.
If Adam had held
the victim underwater
while wearing this robe,
well, the water would
probably have come up to there.
But if someone taller,
someone like you had done it,
I bet the water would
only have come up to...
about there.
Thank you.
That doesn't prove
anything, does it?
When you drowned that
poor girl, something got wet
besides the bottom
of the sleeves, didn't it?
Hey, I didn't drown anyone.
You know, the other day
when I asked you the time
I noticed that your watch
didn't match the
tan line on your arm.
I got to wondering what happened
to the watch you used to wear.
So my associate
did some checking.
You took a watch in for
repair March 6th, didn't you?
Now, easy Mr. Sinclair.
There it is.
Your jeweler hadn't repaired it.
He's backlogged.
That's your watch, isn't it?
Yeah, it looks like my watch.
What's wrong with it?
It stopped.
Why'd it do that?
I don't know, that's
why I took it in.
Tell us what time
the watch stopped.
Four-oh-one.
That's approximately
the time the coroner said
that Debra O'Keefe died.
That's when you
killed her, wasn't it?
That's when you closed
your hands around her neck,
wearing this robe with the
sleeves almost to your elbows,
and forced her
head under the water,
wasn't it?
Wasn't it, Josh?
Your Honor, in light of
the exculpatory evidence
presented at this hearing,
the State respectfully
moves to dismiss charges
against Adam Gardner.
Motion granted.
Case dismissed.
Court adjourned.
Get him out of here.
Good work, Ben.
I don't mind telling
you I'm impressed.
I bet we could throw
each other a lot of business
if you were to make
this move permanent.
What do you think, Tyler?
I'd be dead in a
week, let's go home.
www.tvsubtitles.net